# Henry T. Phan

Atlanta, GA

678-568-1287 • htphan.dev@gmail.com Portfolio: htphan.com

#### **PROFILE**

Passionate, inquisitive, and driven software developer with the personal philosophy that code can always be refactored, there are always more things to learn, and one should never be complacent. Experienced in full-stack Ruby on Rails web application development on relational databases with clean and maintainable code and the ability to quickly learn, master, and adapt to new technologies.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Haml, Markdown

Frameworks: Rails, Sinatra, Bootstrap, Materialize

Databases: Relational Databases, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, Redis

Operating Systems: Windows, Unix, Linux

Others: TDD, Web Development, Object-Oriented Design, RESTful API Development, MVC fundamentals, Webscraping, Heroku,

jQuery, Ajax, JSON, Version Control (Git), Github, OAuth, Multithreading, MiniTest

### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCES**

**Ruby on Rails Student** May 2015 - Present The Iron Yard Atlanta, GA

The Iron Yard is a 12-week intensive programming course aimed at preparing students with the skills of a junior level software developer and training them in approaching and solving problems like a developer.

- Developed a RESTful API for a group project, Convoy, which also involved iOS and Front End developers. Convoy is an application used to simplify the coordination and communication involved in forming carpools. The technology used on the server-side are, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Mandrill, Redis, Multithreading (Resque/Resque-Scheduler), Mailer, JSON, and Heroku.
- Collaborated on a RESTful API for a group project, DCRYPTr, which also involved iOS and Front End developers. DCRYPTr was a game that allowed users to upload abstract pictures and have others guess what they were. The technology used in the server-side are, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Amazon AWS S3, JSON, and Heroku.
- Collaborated on a RESTful API for a group project, BeatDatBudget, which also involved iOS and Front End developers. BeatDatBudget was a game that included a map builder on the web application and the game on the mobile application where software developers are thrown at a 'project' to complete it. The technology used on the server-side are, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Serializer, and Heroku.
- Created a full-stack web application called JustDoDat, which was a simple to-do list tracker. It included user registration, multiple list creation and its corresponding tasks, and simple customization and editing. The technology used for this application are, Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, Devise, and PostgreSQL.
- Engineered many other applications and scripts that used other tech such as OAuth, API consumption (Facebook, Google, Github, Etsy, etc.), OmniAuth, and MiniTest.

**Ruby Developer** June 2015

National Day of Civic Hacking (Hackathon)

Atlanta, GA Collaborated in building a web scraper for the Fulton County Health Department making restaurant inspection scores open source.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Imaging Workflow Specialist** Emory Johns Creek Hospital

Managed the Community Division Radiologists with daily direction of workflow and responsibilities.

August 2013 - May 2015 Johns Creek, GA

Maintained the imaging archives/databases of both the Emory Enterprise (GE PACS) pertaining to the Community Division, and the external Teleradiology locations (NovaPACS) and its associated imaging work lists.

September 2011 - August 2013

Johns Creek, GA

Emory Johns Creek Hospital - Emory Heart and Vascular Center/Interventional Radiology Assisted multiple principal investigators on clinical trails based in Interventional Radiology.

## **Radiology Assistant** Emory Johns Creek Hospital

September 2011 - August 2013

Johns Creek, GA

Assisted Physicians, Technologists, and Nurses with procedures, exams, and its coordination.

# **EDUCATION**

The University of Georgia Bachelor of Science, Biology December 2011